okay there we go okay I know the
好吧，我们去吧，我知道
previous session ran long
上届会议进行了很长时间
and I'm assuming some people are still
我假设有些人还在
out getting their break drinks and
出去喝点饮料，
treats and stuff so when I got to get
对待和东西，所以当我得到
started because we only have 35 minutes
开始，因为我们只有35分钟
I and I want to make sure I get through
我和我想确保我通过
everything so today's presentation is
一切，今天的演讲是
Jakarta EE not your parents Java EE give
Jakarta EE不是您的父母Java EE给予的
a little bit of background on myself
自己的背景
I've been working in this area for a
我一直在这方面工作
long time whether it's the application
长时间是否是应用程序
servers the individual Java EE
服务器各个Java EE
components the jacquard EEE mica profile
提花EEE云母轮廓
I've been involved in a lot of this
我参与了很多
stuff over the years I'm based in the
这些年来，我在
Rochester Minnesota lab and one of the
明尼苏达州罗切斯特实验室和实验室之一
things that I'm finding out from people
我从人们身上发现的东西
talking at this conference most people
大多数人在这次会议上讲话
think of Rochester New York when I've
当我想起纽约罗切斯特
mentioned Rochester so Rochester
提到罗切斯特，所以罗切斯特
Minnesota is actually in the middle of
明尼苏达州实际上位于
the United States we're up towards
我们正在走向的美国
Canada but you know not quite there and
加拿大，但您不知道那里和
so that helps some people but then
这样可以帮助一些人，但是
they're kind of wondering okay why is
他们想知道为什么
IBM in this you know little town of
IBM在这个您知道的小镇
Rochester well one of the things we are
罗切斯特是我们的一件事
home to the Mayo Clinic so maybe you
梅奥诊所的家，所以也许你
have heard of that Medical Center it's
听说过那个医疗中心
kind of world renown and so that's the
世界闻名，这就是
home of the Mayo Clinic is Rochester
梅奥诊所的所在地是罗切斯特
Minnesota so hopefully that gives a
明尼苏达州因此希望给
little better idea of where I am from I
关于我来自哪里的更好的主意
have to give a little bit of background
必须提供一点背景
on the name when I first proposed this
我第一次提出这个名字时
and I proposed it to Eclipse con France
我把它推荐给Eclipse con France
first and then it got picked up for
首先，然后拿起
Eclipse kind of Europe as well I
Eclipse也像欧洲一样
submitted this title and it's a jacquard
提交了这个标题，这是一个提花
EEE not your father's Java EE well for
EEE不适合您父亲的Java EE
those of us from the United States this
我们这些来自美国的人
is kind of a common advertising theme
是一种常见的广告主题
that has been going on for years in the
这已经持续了多年
early 70s Oldsmobile came out with it
70年代初期，Oldsmobile推出了它
originally saying that you know their
最初是说你知道他们的
new oldsmobile is not your father's
新奥尔德莫比尔不是你父亲的
Oldsmobile and that concept started back
奥兹莫比尔（Oldsmobile），这个概念开始了
in the 70s moving forward even computer
在70年代甚至计算机向前发展
companies like HP picked up on it and
像HP这样的公司选择了
they started using it to advertise their
他们开始用它做广告
new computer and even today this is
新电脑，甚至今天
current there's a couple of drinks that
目前有几杯饮料
are available in the night
晚上有空
States for not your father's root beer
国家不是你父亲的生啤酒
or not your mom's apple pie so I just
还是你妈妈的苹果派，所以我只是
thought this was just a well-known
认为这只是一个众所周知的
advertising slogan and so that's why I
广告口号，这就是为什么我
called it not your father's Java EE well
称它不是您父亲的Java EE好
the program committee got back to me and
程序委员会回到我身边，
they said okay we like your abstract but
他们说好吧，我们喜欢您的摘要，但
your title isn't very inclusive and I at
您的头衔不是很包容，我在
first I didn't know what they were
首先我不知道他们是什么
referring to and then I figured it out
指，然后我想通了
and so I changed it I said okay how
所以我改变了我说好吧
about I call it not your parents Java EE
关于我称它不是您的父母Java EE
and they said winner okay so now you're
他们说胜利者好吧，现在你是
in so that's why I came up with the name
这就是为什么我想出这个名字
I want to talk about Jakarta EE and Java
我想谈一谈Jakarta EE和Java
EE I'm not trying to compare them to say
EE我不是要比较他们说
one is a better than the other I want to
一个比另一个我想要的更好
show we are moving we have moved I mean
显示我们在移动我们在移动
there's it's gonna take a while to
会有一段时间
complete but we are moving to Jakarta EE
完成，但我们正在迁移到雅加达EE
so what is changing from a process
那么过程中正在发生的变化
standpoint from a deliverable standpoint
从交付的角度来看
from an artifact standpoint what is
从工件的角度来看，什么是
going to be different and that's what I
会有所不同，那就是我
want to talk about the move to to
想谈谈搬到
eclipse and to Jakarta EE we eventually
蚀和雅加达EE我们最终
will be moving all the specifications
将移动所有规格
the API is the tcks and the reference
API是tcks和参考
implementations the one hiccup that we
实现我们的一个打h
have right now are the specifications
现在有规格
it's a licensing legal issue with Oracle
这是Oracle的许可法律问题
and I'm not going to get into it because
而且我不会参与其中，因为
I don't know the details eventually we
最终我不知道细节
will get that information but that's the
将获得该信息，但这就是
hiccup right now the rest of it all of
现在打ic，其余的全部
the code for the API is all the tcks all
API的代码全部
the reference implementation everything
参考实现的一切
has been moved over to eclipse so we are
已经移到日蚀，所以我们是
making fantastic progress from a coding
通过编码取得了惊人的进步
standpoint we just don't have all the
立场，我们只是没有所有
documentation for the specs available
可用规格的文档
yet people have asked us or told us and
但是人们已经问过我们或告诉过我们，
said well what's so difficult about this
说得好，这有什么困难
all the Java EE stuff was already in
所有的Java EE东西都已经存在
github why can't you just change
github为什么你不能改变
ownership and you're done
所有权，您就完成了
that well a lot of that code that was in
里面的很多代码
those repositories for Java EE it was
这些用于Java EE的存储库是
owned by Oracle and they had to make
由甲骨文拥有，他们不得不
sure that it was clean to contribute to
确保干净有助于
eclipse so there's a lot of code
蚀，所以有很多代码
scanning that had to be done had to make
必须进行的扫描
sure that the licensing was okay that
确保许可是可以的
the copyrights were okay I mean we're
版权还可以，我是说我们
still finding that not all the
仍然发现不是所有的
copyrights were caught and they were you
版权被抓住了，他们就是你
know we still have to clean up some of
知道我们仍然需要清理一些
those we have to prove the certificate
那些我们必须证明证书的
of originality does Oracle do they have
Oracle具有的创意
the rights to contribute it to an open
为公开做出贡献的权利
source foundation so there's a lot of
源基础，所以有很多
background work that had to be done
必须要做的背景工作
other than just changing ownership of
除了改变所有权
the repositories once we get moving on
一旦我们继续前进，仓库
that then we have to follow the Eclipse
那我们必须遵循Eclipse
process and that's for creating a
过程，这是为了创建一个
project we have to do a proposal if we
项目，如果我们必须做一个建议
do a proposal today it's not going to
今天做一个提案不会
the project is not going to get created
该项目将不会被创建
tomorrow it has to go through a review
明天它必须经过审查
process to make sure that this fits
确保合适的过程
within the scheme of Eclipse does it fit
Eclipse的方案内是否适合
within the overall top-level project of
在整个顶级项目中
what you're proposing is it consistent
你的建议是一致的
with the direction of Eclipse so there's
Eclipse的方向，所以有
a lot of things that have to be
很多必须要做的事情
discussed in order to get a proposal
讨论以便获得建议
accepted once it's accepted it's been
被接受，一旦被接受
through the approval process then we go
通过批准过程，然后我们开始
through the provisioning part and that's
通过供应部分，那就是
where the more fun happens where we get
在哪里获得更多乐趣
the repositories created the code gets
创建代码的存储库
moved over we can start building it
移到我们可以开始建造它了
start testing it and eventually create a
开始测试它并最终创建一个
release with eclipse so this chart here
用eclipse释放，所以此图表在这里
shows our current status with moving
通过移动显示我们的当前状态
everything over to eclipse
一切都黯然失色
this shows 39 projects it continues to
这显示了它继续进行的39个项目
grow every week or month I mean we're
每周或每月增长，我是说我们
coming up with another project either
要么想出另一个项目
we're breaking in apart or a new one is
我们正在分崩离析，或者是一个新的
coming in and it's you know we keep
进来，这是你知道我们保持
increasing that but this is really the
增加，但这确实是
core I don't see it growing considerably
核心，我认为它没有显着增长
more than this you'll notice that most
不仅如此，您还会注意到
of the projects are at 80% the hundred
的项目占百分之八十
percent mark
百分率
okay you have done any clips release you
好的，您已经完成了所有剪辑的发布
have finally gotten to the end of this
终于结束了
cycle and you have followed the Eclipse
周期，并且您遵循了Eclipse
process for doing a release the first
首先进行发布的过程
projects I did that were the ones that
我所做的项目就是
were already part of Eclipse that was
已经是Eclipse的一部分，
pretty easy so we've got eclipse link
很简单，所以我们有蚀链接
and json p and json b and yes and those
和json p和json b，是的，那些
were already existing projects in
在已经存在的项目中
eclipse so it was very easy for them to
蚀，所以他们很容易
complete a release but you also notice
完成发行，但您也会注意到
that jax-rs and servlet so they're kind
那个jax-rs和servlet，所以他们很友善
of out in the front and they're saying
在前面，他们说
okay we kind of understand what's going
好吧，我们有点了解发生了什么
on with the eclipse we understand the
关于日食，我们了解
process so we're completing that and
过程，所以我们要完成
they've done their first release
他们已经完成了第一次发行
actually jax-rs has had two releases
实际上jax-rs有两个版本
already the other ones are coming very
已经有其他人来了
soon and one of the whoops one of the
很快，其中之一
things that we are getting to is having
我们要拥有的东西
all of the projects available in order
所有可用项目按顺序
to build Eclipse GlassFish that's the
建立Eclipse GlassFish
goal so one of the things that was just
目标，所以其中之一就是
announced earlier well late last week
上周晚些时候宣布
early this week sometime over the
本周初的某个时候
weekend was release candidate one for
周末是发布候选影片之一
Eclipse GlassFish 5.1 so what that shows
Eclipse GlassFish 5.1如此显示
is that all of the code for GlassFish
是GlassFish的所有代码
has been brought over and we are
已经带来了，我们是
building with everything that is within
用里面的一切建造
eclipse and that's a major item because
日食，这是一个重要的项目，因为
before yeah we could build Eclipse what
是的，在我们可以构建Eclipse之前，
we were pulling things from other
我们从其他地方拉东西
repositories and now we're pulling
存储库，现在我们要拉
everything from within Eclipse so it's
一切都来自Eclipse，因此
really an eclipse deliverable so we've
确实是日食的交付，所以我们已经
got the first rc1 candidate you can go
得到了你可以去的第一个RC1候选人
out and take a look at it download it
看看它下载
try it out give us feedback because we
试试看给我们反馈，因为我们
want to continue to finish the release
想要继续完成发布
for 5.11
为5.11
the things that we're going to do with
我们要做的事情
Eclipse class fish five point one is we
蚀类鱼五点一是我们
want to make it Java EE eight compatible
想要使其与Java EE八兼容
we're going to go through a couple of
我们将经历几个
step process on this the first thing is
第一步，这是
we want to make sure that's Java EE
我们要确保这是Java EE
eight compliant what the goal is most of
八个合规目标是什么
you probably realize that for Java EE
您可能意识到对于Java EE
there's a compatibility page in all the
所有的页面中都有一个兼容性页面
various projects and vendors that are
各种项目和供应商
Java EE eight compatible they submit the
Java EE八兼容他们提交了
results to Oracle and they say hey
结果给甲骨文，他们说嘿
please put us on your page there's a
请把我们放在您的页面上
compatibility page and then you know the
兼容性页面，然后您知道
excuse me the IBM websphere the Red Hat
请问IBM Websphere Red Hat
JBoss all these different projects they
JBoss所有这些不同的项目
are put on that page to indicate
放在该页面上以指示
compliance we want to see the Jakarta EE
我们希望看到Jakarta EE的合规性
logo up there or maybe it'll be Eclipse
那里的徽标，也许是Eclipse
GlassFish I mean I don't know exactly
GlassFish我的意思是我不完全知道
what it is but the deliverable that we
什么是可交付的东西
build via Eclipse GlassFish we want that
通过Eclipse GlassFish构建我们想要的
to be Java EE eight compliant first okay
首先要符合Java EE 8
so that's step one the next thing that
所以这是下一步
we want to do is all those tests that we
我们要做的就是所有这些测试
contributed to eclipse we want to be
促成我们想要成为的日食
able to build that test suite within
能够在内部构建该测试套件
Eclipse so that we have a Jakarta ee8
Eclipse，以便我们拥有Jakarta ee8
test compliance suite okay so yes the
测试合规套件好，是的
code should be the same well we got to
代码应该和我们得到的一样好
make sure that we can build it within
确保我们可以在其中构建它
eclipse so that's the difference between
日食，这是之间的区别
these two compliance steps the first one
这两个合规步骤第一个
will be getting the test from Oracle
将从Oracle获得测试
that says yeah your Java EE eight
说的是，您的Java EE八
compliant now we got to build our own
现在我们必须建立自己的
test suite and make sure that we're
测试套件，并确保我们
Jakarta ee8 compliant so it's a two-step
符合Jakarta EE8，所以它需要两个步骤
process once we do step two then the
一旦完成第二步，然后
other vendors that are interested that
其他感兴趣的供应商
have been Java EE eight compliant they
他们已经兼容Java EE 8
will want to run the new test suite to
将要运行新的测试套件以
say hey yeah I'm also Jakarta ee 8
说嘿，我也是雅加达ee 8
compliant
符合
another big difference is licensing the
另一个很大的不同是许可
AP is the reference implementations and
AP是参考实现，
the specs they were available publicly
他们公开的规格
from Oracle a usage license either be a
从Oracle获得的使用许可可以是
CD DL or GPL was dual licensed you'll
CD DL或GPL获得双重许可，您将
notice the tcks
注意提示
were not available before unless you
除非您之前不可用
sign some type of commercial license
签署某种类型的商业许可证
with Oracle you did not have access to
使用Oracle，您无权访问
the tcks so you could not verify that
提示，因此您无法验证
your implementation works unless you did
您的实现有效，除非您做了
a license with Oracle and then you were
甲骨文的许可证，然后
not allowed access to the Java EE brand
不允许访问Java EE品牌
either so it was a it was a process that
要么这是一个过程，
yes there were many vendors that signed
是的，有很多供应商签署了
up but there were also a subset of
上升，但也有一部分
vendors that either couldn't or wouldn't
不能或不会的供应商
pay the licensing fee to Oracle in order
按顺序向Oracle支付许可费
to pass a TCK so what's different I
通过TCK，那么我有什么不同
mentioned all the T CK's are now in
提到所有的T CK现在都在
Eclipse even even me as a developer at
Eclipse甚至是我在
IBM we had access to the tcks
IBM我们可以使用tcks
but it was a separate team they had
但这是一个独立的团队
access to it myself as a developer I had
我自己作为开发人员可以访问它
no idea what code was actually being run
不知道实际上正在运行什么代码
to test my product if a failure happened
测试我的产品是否发生故障
all that I could do is talk to my test
我所能做的就是跟我的考试谈谈
team and say ok this test is failing can
团队，说好，这个测试失败了
you give me any clue as to what to look
你给我任何关于外表的线索
for and they would look at their test
为了，他们会看他们的测试
case and they'd say well take a look at
情况，他们会说好看看
this section of the spec and see if you
规范的这一部分，看看您是否
think you're as satisfying it that's the
认为您很满意，这就是
type of help that I got I couldn't look
我看不到的帮助类型
at the source code now we can we can go
现在在源代码中，我们可以开始
out to eclipse if a test fails I can
如果测试失败，我可以忽略
look at it and say oh wow they're
看着它说哦，他们是
testing that aspect we're and you know
测试我们所处的方面，您知道
does expect really say that that's a
确实期望真的说那是
monster as it should or whatever so
怪物，无论如何
that's going to be fantastic for all of
这对于所有的人来说都是很棒的
us that are trying to be compliant with
试图遵守的我们
Jakarta ee8 now I mentioned that no
雅加达EE8现在我提到了
commercial license would be needed
需要商业许可证
that's not entirely true because there
这并不完全正确，因为那里
will need to be some type of license
将需要某种类型的许可证
with eclipse we're still working through
与日食，我们仍在努力
the details on that
细节
there needs to be some type of license
需要某种类型的许可证
to protect the Jakarta ee brand so there
保护雅加达ee品牌，所以在那里
will be something that people vendors
将是人贩子
individuals will have to agree with with
个人将不得不同意
eclipse but it's not going to be a
食，但这不会是
monetary thing that that you have to
你必须要的金钱
sign up for but there does have to be
注册，但必须有
something in place to protect that brand
保护该品牌的措施
I'll touch on some of these older
我会讲一些这些较老的
processes within the JC P so the JC P is
JC P中的流程，因此JC P是
what governed the Java EE process we now
是什么主导了我们现在的Java EE流程
have eclipse that's going to govern the
食将要统治
Eclipse process for Jakarta EE I'm going
我要去的Jakarta EE的Eclipse流程
to touch on just a few items from the
只需触摸一下
JCP process the JCP the j srs and the
JCP处理JCP，JSR和
JSP a the participation agreement and
JSP的参与协议和
how is that going to be different with
与...有什么不同
eclipse so if you listen to Mike's
蚀，所以如果你听麦克的
presentation yesterday the the keynote
昨天的主题演讲
he talked about working groups and
他谈到了工作组，
there's several working groups within
有几个工作组
the Eclipse organization IOT is one of
Eclipse组织的物联网是其中之一
them I I know
他们我知道
Jakarta EE is a working group so you can
Jakarta EE是一个工作组，因此您可以
kind of think of the working group as
认为工作组是
being equivalent to the JC P so whatever
等同于JC P
rules and regulations at the JC P had we
JC P的规章制度让我们
have to have something similar within
必须有类似的东西
Eclipse now we are not trying to
Eclipse现在我们不尝试
duplicate the JC P we know that there
复制JC P，我们知道那里
were problems with the JC P and the
JC P和
process and the slowness of getting
过程和获取的缓慢
stuff approved or changed through that
通过批准或更改的内容
process we are trying to do a better job
我们试图做得更好的过程
we are getting input from a lot of
我们从很多方面得到输入
different organizations to make that
不同的组织来做到这一点
better sometimes oh yeah there's process
有时候更好，是的，有过程
that's going to have to be put in place
必须将其放置到位
in order to protect the brand some key
为了保护品牌一些关键
things that we're looking at though
我们正在寻找的东西
vendor-neutral okay I know the JCP was a
与供应商无关好的，我知道JCP是
separate organization
独立组织
from Oracle but Oracle control the JCP
从Oracle，但是Oracle控制JCP
all of the IP from the JCP flowed to
来自JCP的所有IP都流向了
Oracle and Oracle relicensing it out to
Oracle和Oracle将其许可给
everybody we're not doing it that way
每个人我们都没有那样做
with eclipse it's going to be vendor
与蚀它将是供应商
neutral it's going to be a more flexible
中性它将变得更加灵活
flow of IP through the process and we
整个流程中的IP流，我们
want to make sure that we continue that
想要确保我们继续
the jsr that's the Java specification
Java规范的jsr
request this is a way that we did our
要求这是我们做到的方式
designs for Java EE oh one thing I
Java EE的设计哦，我有一件事
forgot to point out on the previous
忘了指出前一个
slide all these things I'm talking about
滑动我正在谈论的所有这些事情
with the JCP the JSI our JSP a all of
与JCP，JSI，我们的JSP
those will continue to exist they are
那些将继续存在，他们是
not going away they will be targeted
不走开，他们将成为目标
more for Java SE than Java EE of course
当然，Java SE比Java EE还要多
but they're not going away so I don't
但他们不会消失，所以我不会
want you to get the impression that you
希望您得到您的印象
know eclipse is taking over the JCP we
知道日食正在接管我们的JCP
are only providing the the subset for
只提供以下子集
Java EE or Jakarta EE
Java EE或Jakarta EE
so the jsr is going to be replaced with
因此，jsr将被替换为
the specification process okay this is
规范过程好吧，这是
what we have been working really night
晚上我们一直在努力
and day on in order to try to come up
和一天以尝试出现
with a draft before eclipse Khan and
在日食之前先准备好汗和
Mike mentioned this yesterday that we
迈克昨天提到这个，我们
have a public draft available came out
有可用的公开草案
middle of last week please even just
上周中旬请
take a read through it even if you don't
即使您不阅读它，也请仔细阅读
think that you know this doesn't apply
以为你知道这不适用
to me take a read and see if you think
给我看书，看看你是否认为
you know is a flowing rate as a making
你知道流动率
sense because you never know when you're
感觉，因为你永远不知道你什么时候
going to be dependent on this new
将依赖于这个新
specification process and we would love
规范过程，我们很乐意
input we're looking for input to end by
我们正在寻找输入的结尾
the end of the month then we have to
月底，那么我们必须
bring all that stuff together go through
汇集所有东西通过
the review comments try to get a new
评论评论尝试获取新的
revision and then hopefully if it's
修订，然后希望是
nothing too major we'll come out with a
没什么大不了的，我们会提出一个
proposed final draft that we can then
建议的最终草案，然后我们可以
distribute to the community
分发给社区
the other thing that we have done is we
我们要做的另一件事是我们
have signed up a guinea-pig project jano
已经签署了几内亚猪项目贾诺
sequel is actually an eclipse
续集实际上是日食
implementation project right now what
现在的实施项目
they are willing and wanting to try out
他们愿意并想要尝试
the new specification process they are
他们是新的规范过程
willing to roll it with the punches
愿意用拳打滚
they know there's going to be some
他们知道会有一些
hiccups they know that they might have
他们知道自己可能有打ic
to you know maybe even redo rework some
你知道甚至可以重做一些
stuff as we're trying to figure out if
的东西，因为我们试图找出是否
the process works but the team seems
该过程有效，但团队似乎
very willing to work with us and they
非常愿意与我们合作，他们
want to try it out so I think it'll be a
想尝试一下，所以我认为这将是一个
bonus for both of us they get to be the
对我们俩来说，奖金都是
first ones and then we can test out the
首先，然后我们可以测试
process the other thing the JSP a that
处理JSP的另一件事
had to be signed by every member company
必须由每个成员公司签署
or individual that was working on a jsr
或从事jsr工作的个人
and what this did this help define the
这有助于定义什么
IP flow from all the contributions that
来自所有贡献的知识产权流
are going into the Jai SRS and being
正在进入Jai SRS并被
able to get you know into Oracle and
能够使您了解Oracle和
then they can distribute it back out
然后他们可以将其分发出去
through their licensing mechanism we're
通过他们的许可机制，我们
going to have something similar and I
会有类似的东西，我
put it in quotes up here because I don't
把它放在这里，因为我不
think we've defined an exact name yet
认为我们已经定义了确切的名称
but whether it's a modification to the
但是否是对
Eclipse contribution agreement or if
Eclipse贡献协议或
we're gonna have a new participation
我们将有一个新的参与
agreement type thing but something will
协议类型的东西，但会
need to be done for specification
需要完成规范
projects because the IP flow for
之所以进行项目，是因为
specifications it's a little different
规格有点不同
than what you have just for code
比仅用于代码的内容
speaking of specs one thing that we
说到规格，我们要做的一件事
learned I was at John's presentation
得知我在约翰的演讲中
yesterday and he pointed out the same
昨天，他指出了同样的道理
little issue back in j2 e 1.4 maybe even
j2 e 1.4中的小问题甚至
before that there was a lot of specs
在此之前，有很多规格
that were written for j2ee at that time
当时为j2ee编写的
that did not have an implementation to
没有实现
prove that it was doable I mean yes they
证明这是可行的，我的意思是，他们
had they eventually have a reference
他们最终是否有参考
implementation but it just didn't build
实施，但它没有建立
upon industry experience one example of
以行业经验为例
that is like a JB's and entity beans
就像JB和实体bean
I put kind of a tough word up there
我在那儿说了一个很难的话
saying that have failed I I know we have
说失败了我知道我们有
customers that are still using that
仍在使用的客户
technology but from a interoperability
技术，但来自互操作性
perspective that just did not work every
只是不起作用的观点
implementation of EJB entity beans
EJB实体bean的实现
whether it was from IBM or red hat or
无论是从IBM还是red hat还是
WebLogic at they were not compatible you
他们的WebLogic与您不兼容
had to rewrite your beans if you're
如果你要的话，不得不重写你的bean
gonna move from one platform to another
要从一个平台转移到另一个平台
now compare that to what we did in Java
现在将其与我们在Java中所做的进行比较
EE 5 with EJB 3 and JPA
带有EJB 3和JPA的EE 5
now that was built upon industry
现在是建立在行业基础上的
experience especially with hibernate for
经验特别是冬眠
JPA
JPA
and they participated in the creation of
他们参与了
that specification and we brought that
该规范，我们带来了
in we were able to work through it we
我们能够通过它
have a very usable persistence model now
现在有一个非常有用的持久性模型
and it's been in place for several years
已经存在好几年了
so that's what I want to really
这就是我真正想要的
emphasize with the new Eclipse process
用新的Eclipse流程强调
is we want to have some type of code
我们是否想要某种类型的代码
first we want whether you're doing it as
首先，我们想知道您是否正在这样做
part of your individual projects or as a
您个人项目的一部分或作为
separate project out in the industry
行业中的独立项目
something to show that the idea is
一些东西表明这个想法是
worthwhile and it's ready or good to be
值得，准备好或做好准备
standardized that's what we want to
标准化就是我们想要的
drive towards so speaking of that we
朝着我们这样说
have another sister project out there
还有另一个姊妹项目
called micro profile I won't go into a
叫做微个人资料，我不会
lot of detail on the comparison or the
比较或
relationship between micro profile and
微观轮廓与
jacquard EEE
提花EEE
if you want to get into more detail on
如果您想进一步了解
that I have another presentation this
我有另一个演讲
afternoon I think is that 3:45 right
下午我认为是3:45对
right behind me on that stage so if you
在那个阶段就在我后面，如果你
want to get into more detail please come
想了解更多细节，请过来
then but what I want to talk about here
那我想在这里说什么
is that micro profile has kind of blazed
微小的轮廓有光泽
the way for the processes that we're
流程的方式
defining for Jakarta EE we did a lot of
为Jakarta EE定义我们做了很多
experimentation and innovation with
实验与创新
micro profile that now we are looking at
现在我们正在查看的微型配置文件
is it ready to be standardized so one of
准备好进行标准化了吗？
the first things that we did was with
我们要做的第一件事是
the config JSI or the the config portion
config JSI或config部分
of micro profile we proposed that as a
微观轮廓，我们建议
jsr well that was before oracle decided
jsr很好，那是在Oracle决定之前
to open source java EE so we were
开源java EE，所以我们
following the old process but now does
遵循旧流程，但现在可以
it make sense that maybe that config jsr
有道理，也许配置jsr
maybe it should be moved over to the new
也许应该将其移至新
Eclipse specification process and it
Eclipse规范过程及其
should become part of Jakarta EE that's
应该成为Jakarta EE的一部分
something that's being discussed I'm not
正在讨论的东西我不是
I'm not saying that's a done deal but
我并不是说这已经完成了，但是
that's the type of thing that we're
那就是我们所要做的事情
looking at for the for this relationship
寻找这种关系
now micah profile Jakarta EE you know
现在micah档案Jakarta EE你知道
are we going to stop like a profile
我们要像个人资料一样停下来吗
just because we're working on Jakarta EE
只是因为我们正在开发Jakarta EE
and absolutely not
绝对不是
in June we came out with two major
在六月，我们提出了两个主要
releases of micro profile 1.4 2.0 the
micro profile 1.4 2.0版本的发布
individual components underneath them
它们下面的各个组件
were exactly the same the difference is
完全一样，区别是
what version of Java EE was a based off
Java EE是基于什么版本的
of so 1.4 is based off of Java EE 7 2.0
之所以1.4是基于Java EE 7 2.0
was based off of Java EE 8 so we have
基于Java EE 8，因此我们拥有
continued to make progress with micro
继续在微型方面取得进展
profile as Jakarta EE continues to
Jakarta EE继续
evolve as a matter of fact just last
事实上发展到最后
week we completed another release of
一周，我们完成了
micah profile 2.1 now you notice we only
micah profile 2.1现在您只注意到我们
have one item up there open tracing one
上面有一件物品公开追踪
of the things that we have decided from
我们已经决定的事情
micah profile perspective is to do to do
micah个人资料观点是要做的事
time boxed releases so whatever is ready
盒装发布，所以一切准备就绪
that's what we're going to ship at the
这就是我们要在
time of doing micro profile to point
进行微轮廓分析的时间
we only had open tracing one-point-two
我们只有公开追踪一分二分
available we we did talk about it as a
可用，我们确实将其称为
team and we said okay is that enough and
团队，我们说还可以，
it's like no we decided right up front
就像不，我们提前决定
we're gonna do time box releases so
我们要发布时间盒，以便
that's what we stuck with one other
那就是我们彼此坚持的东西
thing that came out of that discussion
讨论产生的东西
though is that just for your awareness
虽然那只是为了您的意识
next year we're going to cut back to
明年我们将减少到
three releases per year for micro
每年三个版本
profile we're gonna do a February June
我们要去二月六月的个人资料
and October and I know that's kind of
和十月，我知道那是
weird we're kind of calling it our
很奇怪，我们有点称呼我们
conference driven releases because
会议驱动版本，因为
there's conferences in springtime
春天有会议
February we've got some in summertime
二月我们夏天有空
for the June and then we've got the fall
六月，然后秋天
conferences and so October so that's
会议等等，所以十月
what we decided to go for for micro
我们决定去微型市场
profile I don't have a church for this
我没有为此的教堂
but I got to give another plug to mica
但是我得再给云母加个插头
profile you know some of you guys know
您知道的个人资料，有些人知道
there's another conference going on in
还有另一个会议正在进行
San Francisco you know used to be Java
你知道旧金山曾经是Java
one now it's Oracle code one mica
现在是Oracle代码一号云母
profile one a Dukes Choice Award it was
曾获杜克斯选择奖
just announced last night so I think
昨晚刚刚宣布，所以我认为
that's pretty cool I want to talk a
我想谈一个很酷
little bit about the teams that are
关于那支球队的一点点
within the Eclipse Foundation there's a
在Eclipse Foundation中，有一个
little bit of confusion between you'll
你们之间会有些混乱
hear the term Jakarta EE
听到Jakarta EE一词
then you'll he'll hear the term EE 4j
然后他会听到EE 4j一词
and what is the difference the Jakarta
和雅加达有什么区别
EE is the brand name that's the working
EE是最有效的品牌名称
group so within the working group we
在工作组中，我们
have a steering committee that oversees
有一个指导委员会来监督
all of the activities we've got the
我们进行的所有活动
specification committee we have the
规格委员会，我们有
marketing committee it's that whole
营销委员会就这样
brand for that that for Jakarta ee ee 4j
雅加达ee ee 4j的品牌
was a name that we came up with when the
是我们在
code and stuff was first getting moved
代码和东西首先被移动
over to eclipse we didn't have a brand
黯然失色，我们没有品牌
name yet we had to name it something
名字，但我们不得不给它起个名字
that was legal we couldn't call it Java
那是合法的，我们不能称它为Java
Enterprise or anything like that because
企业之类的，因为
I had the word Java in it so we came up
我里面有Java一词，所以我们来了
with EE 4j and that's our top level
EE 4j，这是我们的最高水平
project in Eclipse okay so that's more
Eclipse中的项目还可以，所以还有更多
of a
的
I don't know if you wanna call an
我不知道你是否想打电话
implementation detail but you know it's
实施细节，但是你知道
more just for the projects within
更适合于内部的项目
eclipse now if you're just talking to
如果您只是在与之交谈，请立即食
your friends you could say EE for J or
您的朋友，您可以为J说EE或
Jakarta EE and basically you're talking
Jakarta EE，基本上你在说
about the same thing within eclipse we
关于日食的同一件事
know that there's a difference but out
知道有区别但是
in the industry you could probably get
在这个行业你可能会得到
away with using either term there are a
离开使用任何一个术语有一个
couple of links if you want to read more
几个链接，如果您想阅读更多
about this relationship between the two
关于两者之间的这种关系
so one thing that I want to mention
我想提一件事
let's see okay got a few more minutes
让我们再等几分钟
talk about the participation level of
说说参与程度
these two communities I first wanted to
我首先想要的这两个社区
go out and look and say okay who makes
出去看看，说好吧，谁让
up the Java EE community and this was
Java EE社区，这是
kind of eye-opening I was I was trying
我当时在尝试让我大开眼界
to find a page that would show all of
查找可以显示所有内容的页面
the companies that are participating in
参与的公司
the Jay SRS and I couldn't find anything
Jay SRS，我什么也找不到
like that and what's kind of weird this
这样，这有点奇怪
is it's a Java EE community page and
这是Java EE社区页面吗？
what company do you see it's only Oracle
您看到的是哪家公司，只有Oracle
that's it
而已
so from a Java EE perspective it really
所以从Java EE的角度来看
was an Oracle run Oracle own process and
是Oracle运行Oracle自己的流程，并且
artifact now take a look at this Jakarta
现在看一下这个雅加达
EE it's a website Jakarta EE if you go
EE，如果您去的话，这是一个网站Jakarta EE
there you will see all of these
在那里你会看到所有这些
companies that are participating now you
现在正在参加的公司
also notice Oracle is up there yes
还注意到甲骨文在那里
Oracle of course is participating
甲骨文当然会参加
they're contributing all this they want
他们正在贡献他们想要的一切
to get this all contributed into eclipse
让这一切都成为日食的原因
but they're at the same level as
但它们与
everybody else it's just one voice they
其他人只是一个声音，他们
don't control everything anymore it's a
不再控制一切了
community of participants and that's a
参与者社区，这是一个
big difference so this portion of the
差异很大，所以这部分
talk I actually I probably have to
说话我实际上我可能不得不
either remove it or change it because
要么删除它，要么更改它，因为
it's getting a little too skewed I first
首先我有点偏斜了
put this together in June because I
六月份放在一起，因为我
wanted to show that the participation
想表明参与
level in the Jakarta EE discussion
Jakarta EE讨论中的级别
groups was more than what we were having
小组比我们拥有的更多
in Java EE
在Java EE中
and and it worked very good in June
而且它在6月份效果很好
you'll notice now that when I start
您现在会注意到，当我开始
comparing the different groups
比较不同的群体
it's just ballooning so fast in Jakarta
雅加达的气球飞快
EE that it's not really a fair
EE，这确实不公平
comparison anymore but I'm still gonna
比较了，但我仍然会
run through it for today's presentation
通过它进行今天的演示
so what I'm trying to do is show the
所以我想做的是显示
different aspects we've got the whole
不同的方面，我们已经得到了整体
community I want to look at that
我想看看的社区
participation level and then let's look
参与程度，然后让我们看一下
at the platform participation level so
在平台参与级别上
that's a little bit smaller and then
有点小，然后
let's look at an individual component
让我们看一个单独的组件
participation level and see how that
参与程度，看看如何
compares so first of all for the overall
比较起来首先
community participation over on the
社区参与
left-hand side you'll notice that the
在左侧，您会注意到
number of subscribers to the mailing
邮件订阅者数量
lists okay so I took all of Java EE and
列出可以，所以我将所有Java EE和
let's see the number was about 600 599
让我们看看这个数字大约是600599
and as of this past week we have 676
截至上周，我们有676
subscribers in all of the community so
所有社区的订阅者
that shows that there is plenty of
这表明有很多
interest in the java jakarta ee
对Java雅加达EE的兴趣
community now if we drop down to the
现在，如果我们下降到
platform level this is getting a little
平台级别这有点
more specific I'm looking at the PMC
更具体地说，我在看PMC
conversations that type of thing you'll
那种类型的对话
still notice that we have a pretty
仍然注意到我们有一个漂亮的
healthy you know what 47 to 84 this has
健康，你知道这47到84
made a jump of about 20 people just
跳了大约20个人
since June that we've had an increase
自六月以来，我们的数量有所增加
and then if we go down to the individual
然后，如果我们下降到个人
component with jax-rs they are even
带有jax-rs的组件，它们甚至
continuing to increase
持续增加
I think they increased by about 10
我认为他们增加了大约10
people since June so there's continued
人们自六月以来，所以继续
increase in participation level so the
增加参与水平，因此
other thing I looked at was the number
我看的另一件事是数字
of messages that were being posted and
被张贴的邮件
this is where it's just really getting
这才是真正要去的地方
skewed out of whack and I I'll just put
歪歪扭扭，我就放
it up here but you know the very first
它在这里，但你首先知道
one over there there was one message
一个在那儿有一条消息
posted to Java EE that said hey we
发布到Java EE，说嘿
released Java EE 8 that's it so no more
发布了Java EE 8，仅此而已
messages so that's why there's only one
信息，这就是为什么只有一个
and then all of the activity within the
然后在
jacquard EEE
提花EEE
it's been you know almost a couple
一直以来你都知道
thousand messages since you know about
千条消息，因为你知道
June when we look at the platform level
六月，我们来看看平台级别
kind of the same thing that has really
有点相同的东西
kind of died off since they announced it
自从他们宣布它以来那种死亡
there's been a few discussions because
进行了一些讨论，因为
of clarifications but not a whole lot a
澄清，但不是很多
lot more participation on our PMC
更多参与我们的PMC
mailing list and then if you go all the
邮件列表，然后如果您去所有
way down to jax-rs same thing they're
直到jax-rs他们都是一样的东西
you know they've died off because jax-rs
你知道他们已经死了，因为jax-rs
2.1 came out with java ee 8 been some
2.1随Java ee 8推出了
little bit of conversation since then
从那以后的一点对话
but most of it has been in our user
但大部分都在我们的用户中
group within jakarta ee the other thing
在雅加达ee内分组另一件事
that shows community participation is
表明社区参与是
even coming up with the name we went
甚至拿出我们去的名字
through a process or trying to come up
通过一个过程或试图提出
okay what's going to be the new name we
好吧，新的名字将会是什么
knew we couldn't use java in the name we
知道我们不能以我们的名字使用Java
can't use java x we you know what what
不能使用Java X我们知道什么
is it that we're going to come up with
是我们要提出的
so we opened an issue and we said put
所以我们打开一个问题，我们说放
your suggestions out there and man did
你的建议在那里，男人做了
we get a lot of them we got you know
我们得到了很多，我们知道了
some of them were pretty rough I mean
他们中有些人很粗糙
they're you know digging each other with
他们是你知道吗
the different names that were being
不同的名字
proposed some of them were already used
建议其中一些已经被使用
by other companies other trademarks some
由其他公司提供的其他商标
were using the word Java or Java X so
使用Java或Java X这个词
there's a lot of them that we were
我们中有很多人
throwing out but we ended up with two
扔出去，但我们最终有两个
names Jakarta EE and enterprise profile
命名雅加达EE和企业简介
and we opened up a community vote for it
我们为此进行了社区投票
and we said okay these are the ones that
我们说好的，这些是
you picked what do you think we ought to
你选择了你认为我们应该怎么做
do and we had seven thousand unique
做，我们有七千个独特的
votes and that had to be unique based on
投票，并且必须基于
email address that was being used and
使用的电子邮件地址和
then they even went so far to make sure
然后他们甚至走到了确保
that they weren't using the trick that
他们没有使用技巧
you know Gmail allows with the plus sign
您知道Gmail允许使用加号
they wanted to make sure that those
他们想确保那些
weren't counted and so we had seven
不算在内，所以我们有七个
thousand unique votes and you know we
一千张独特的选票，你知道我们
came up with the name Jakarta the other
想出了另一个名字雅加达
thing to point out here that was kind of
这里要指出的是
nice is those of you who have been
那些曾经
around for a while
大约一会儿
Jakarta was a project at Apache and it
雅加达是Apache的一个项目，
was related to the old Java Runtime
与旧的Java Runtime有关
library type code well.when OpenJDK a
库类型代码。当OpenJDK
got going that project died off
开始，该项目失败了
so when jakarta came up as a suggestion
所以当雅加达提出建议时
we thought well we can't use that a pass
我们认为很好，我们不能使用该通行证
he already owns it we approached apache
他已经拥有了，我们联系了apache
and you know luckily we've got one of
你很幸运，我们有一个
our guys David Blevins that's very
我们的大卫·布列文（David Blevins）
involved with Apache and he approached
参与Apache，他走近
them and they thought it was a wonderful
他们，他们认为这是一个美妙的
idea so they transferred the ownership
想法，所以他们转让了所有权
over to eclipse and said please do it
食过了，说请做
would be a great way to resurrect that
将是一个伟大的方式来复活
name and that that mentality and so
名字和那种心态等等
that's what we ended up doing the other
那就是我们最终要做的另一件事
thing that we did from a community
我们从社区做的事情
participation viewpoint is we had to
参与观点是我们必须
come up with a logo could no longer use
拿出徽标无法使用
a coffee cup of course now the the
现在当然是一杯咖啡了
unique thing here is that the originally
这里的独特之处在于
Eclipse paid a design team to come up
Eclipse付钱给一个设计团队
with some logos and they were presented
带有一些徽标，并向他们展示了
to the community and the community said
对社区和社区说
oh wait a minute I mean some of us not
哦，等等，我的意思是我们当中有些人没有
me but some of us are kind of artistic
我，但我们当中有些人是艺术的
you know can't we submit other logo
你知道我们不能提交其他徽标
ideas and so we opened it up and other
想法，所以我们打开了它，其他
people contributed other ideas and we
人们贡献了其他想法，我们
ended up having a vote off of I don't
最终对我没有投票
know how many we had oh seven so we had
知道我们有七个哦，所以我们有
seven finalists and we opened it up for
七个决赛入围者，我们为
a vote what was really cool the guy that
投票真是太酷了
one is from Red Hat nothing to do which
一个是从红帽无所事事的
Accardi II he was more of a designer an
Accardi II是他的设计师
artistic guy and he's the one that came
艺术的家伙，他是那个来的
up with our new sailboat so that was
用我们的新帆船，所以
kind of cool because that was all
有点酷，因为那就是全部
community driven so just a complete
社区驱动，所以只是一个完整的
we're going from your parents our
我们要从你父母那里
parents Java EE to Jakarta EE and that's
将Java EE移植到Jakarta EE，那就是
what I had for today don't forget to do
我今天所拥有的不要忘记去做
the evaluation I don't know I might have
我可能不知道的评估
time
时间